

ralecus@uwm.edu

Profile

Dedicated laboratory technician with 6+ years of experience in chemical sciences. Assistant manager for wet chemical labs and clean room facilities. Experienced in the development and characterization of novel porous materials for in-situ water remediation.

Employment History

Jan 2014 — Feb 2020

Milwaukee, WI

Laboratory Prep Technician, Sr. at-University of Wisconsin Milwaukee - Water Technology Accelerator (WaTA)

- Assist with (a) training for new and recurrent users for all WaTA equipment and for equipment in UWM Innovation Campus clean room and Micro-CT scanner and with (b) additional training of equipment for attracting new users.
- Keeps equipment operating by following operating instructions, troubleshooting breakdowns, maintaining supplies, performing preventive maintenance and calling for repairs.
- 3. Supporting activities in shared laboratories:
- 4. Supports students/researchers by maintaining supplies from shared laboratories - glassware, equipment logs, and record books, troubleshooting and resolving problems and helping with special projects.
- 5. Resolves problems by examining and evaluating data and selecting corrective steps.
- Completes projects by assisting project team and attending and participating in group and project meetings.
- 7. Updates job knowledge by participating in educational opportunities, reading technical publications, collaborating in publications.

Jun 2012 — May 2013

Cashier at Pilot Travel Centers

Franklin, WI

- 1. Provide fast and friendly service to customers.
- 2. Maintain a clean environment.

Education

Iun 2013

University of Wisconsin Milwaukee

Milwaukee, WI

Chemistry

Pursuing a bachelor of science in chemistry with a focus on freshwater sciences.

Details

(262) 417 6891

Skills

Research

Management Skills

Secondary Electron

Microscopy

Physisorption

Photolithography

E-beam Deposition

Coatings

Sigma Plot

Jan 2016 — May 2016

Londonderry, County Borough, Northern Ireland

University of Ulster

Irish Studies

Recieved advanced certificate in Irish Studies.

Internships

Jan 2016 — Jul 2016

Bellfast

Student Intern at Northern Ireland Environment Link

The Northern Ireland Environment Link (NIEL) is an environmental agency committed to improving environment quality throughout Northern Ireland. My project was look into the effectiveness of the River Basin Management Project and cost benefit of meeting federal guidelines. I also examined policies implemented in other countries within the European Union to propose effective strategies in the current plan for Northern Ireland. A final report of my findings was submitted at the end of my internship.

Sep 2015 — Jan 2016

*

Newberg, WI

Student Intern at Riveredge Nature Center

This was a case study that investigated the contamination of lead into the rivers of a wildlife sanctuary from a neighboring shooting range. My responsibilities included project design, collaborating with other agencies, sample collection/mapping, and writing technical reports. The results found were insignificant, therefore was never formally published.

References

University of Wisconsin Milwaukee

Barbara J Breed-Heidt

joheidt@uwm.edu (262) 227-6538

University of Wisconsin Milwaukee

Shelby L Lunsford

lunsford@uwm.edu 4146875871

University of Wisconsin Milwaukee

Maixee Yang

yang588@uwm.edu 4143688750